<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Enrique Cepeda</title><link>https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Enrique Cepeda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About goals and expectations</title><link>https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/about-goals-and-expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/about-goals-and-expectations/</guid><description>People have goals and aspirations, is something that defines us as humans. For me, how you approach them is 80% of the work.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not was always the case that I knew how to deal with expectations. Not a long ago, I found myself not getting the job done, or so I thought. The tasks and the goals I had, were never completed for me, and this situation made me anxious and kept me stuck in a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deadlock">deadlock</a>, not making steps because I wasn&rsquo;t happy with my situation.</p>
<p>I tried as hard as I could, but I couldn&rsquo;t get away with the resentment feelings, and working remotely didn&rsquo;t help. But people were happy with my work, in fact, they always had good words about me, &ldquo;how could that be?&rdquo; I didn&rsquo;t feel like I was giving my 100%, but for people it was more than enough.</p>
<p>The only thing that happened was that I was trapped in my own expectations, always trying to do the &ldquo;right thing&rdquo; no matter what, was killing me. I had impostor syndrome on my work and on my personal life, I wasn&rsquo;t always enough and the self-judgment thoughts were going to the roof.</p>
<p>Then I thought, &ldquo;Doesn&rsquo;t people have big goals? There has to be more, we are not that different&rdquo;, and I was right. A better approach was the puzzle piece that was missing. It wasn&rsquo;t realistic for me to achieve all my aspirations fast and at the same time, so at the start of this year, I set myself some goals to achieve by the end of the year, and I&rsquo;ve already completed some of them.</p>
<p>For me, setting myself achievable goals with a fixed deadline is the best way of actually doing something to make them happen. Furthermore, I&rsquo;m learning to deal with the fact that results not always depend on my actions, and that they don&rsquo;t define me as a person. In fact reading, one of these goals, have helped me a lot to deal with these emotions.</p>
<p>I realized that whenever I feel fear or anxiety about something, maybe that&rsquo;s the right path.
Or maybe not the right path, but at least I&rsquo;m taking one, in this case the blog, let&rsquo;s see if it goes somewhere.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The impediment to action advances action. What stands in the way becomes the way.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Be what excites</title><link>https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/be-what-excites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://EnriqueCepeda.github.io/be-what-excites/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about who I want to be, and I&amp;#39;ve come to the conclusion that I want to be what excites me.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One year after finishing college, after starting on my &ldquo;life journey&rdquo; on a 9 to 5 job, I feel is time to reflect on who I want to be.</p>
<p>I have no doubt that all humans try to find ways of spending our time on earth the best way possible. However, there is a lot of distractions that cloud our judgment and tear us apart from our dreams and aspirations. I&rsquo;m no exception.</p>
<p>Each time I notice I&rsquo;m not doing what I should, I feel a sense of dreadfulness inside me. A thought that tells me this one is the last, next time it will be better, but it won&rsquo;t.</p>
<p>Maybe is time to change now, maybe is time to reflect and talk with myself about the things I want in life, and what are my values. About I do, why should I do it or why not.
Why is the case that sometimes I feel stuck in a rut and how I get out of that.</p>
<p>For me, inspiration is a big motivator. I want to do the things that excites me, I want to cook, I want to learn new things, I want to enjoy life with my loved ones, I want to visit beautiful places, I want to live.</p>
<p>This is a message to me and to you. Be what excites you, fight and work for these things and you&rsquo;ll never feel you have to be distracted.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You&rsquo;re what you do, not what you say you&rsquo;ll do.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>